THAGANA MARK KIMARU

Back-end and Web Developer

Mayor RD No 17 Nairobi 4390-0200 +254-726782953, +254-732973772 thagana44@gmail.com , kimaruthagana@outlook.com

ABOUT ME

I am a student of kenyan descent(**National ID 33176079**) currently pursuing a Bachelors of Science degree in computer Science in the University of Nairobi while concurrently working as a programmer dealing majorly with web development in python on the side as programming is my passion since 2015.

Always curious and learning new things in this vast realm of programming with my current interest being machine learning. I always give every project a personal touch as i am not in this only for the financial benefits but for fullfilment of purpose which i take with much gravity as a calling.

SKILLS

- Web scripting and design.
- Algorithm formulation and refinement.
- Program development in python and C++.
- Back-end development in PHP, MYSQL, python and

POSTGRES.

- Program documentation and report writing.
- Web application security.
- Database Design.
- Business process refinement and formulation.
- Interaction with Linux Systems.
- Interaction with GIT.
- API design using Django REST FRAMEWORK(DRF).

EXPERIENCE

Venturi Systems Kenya, Nairobi – Co-Founder and Backend Developer JANUARY 2016 - DATE

- Back-end web development
- Database Design
- Algorithm stepwise refinement
- API Interfacing

Free lance Developer, Nairobi – Website development and maintenance

OCTOBER-2015 to DATE

- Web application development
- Static web design
- General consultancy on matters pertaining websites

EDUCATION

University of Nairobi, Nairobi - Bsc Computer Science

SEPTEMBER-2015 to DATE

Currently pursuing a Bachelors of Science degree in computer Science

Emobilis, Mobile Training Institute, Westlands - Web and mobile debelopment and Entrepreneurship Jan-2015 to JUNE 2015

Graduated with a certificate in Mobile Software Development and Entrepreneurship acquiring skills in web development with PHP, mobile application development in windows and also entrepreneurial skills.

Pioneer School, Maragua - Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education(KCSE)

JANUARY-2011- NOVEMBER 2014

Graduated from high school with a mean grade of an A (plain). An achievement which was recognized in the school's prize giving day in the year 2015

INTERESTS

Major interests include programming, travelling, learning of new cultures and outdoor experiences such as camping.

REFEREES

Pst Timothy Waita Mwongela

+254-729213419

Salome Wanjiku

+254-723201162